Guide to the John R. Mott Papers
Yale University Divinity School Library
- General Correspondence, Series I
  - Alphabetical listing
    - Wilson, Woodid, 1918 (Box 100, Folder 1763)
    - Wilson, Woodid, 1919-1924 (Box 100, Folder 1764)
    - Wishard, Luther D., 1886-1911 (Box 100, Folder 1765)
    - Wolf, Frederick E., 1940-1941 (Box 100, Folder 1766)
    - Wolferz, Louis, 1944-1945 (Box 100, Folder 1767)
    - Wood, Edward C., 1940-1945 (Box 100, Folder 1768)
    - Woodruff, F.P., 1928-1942 (Box 100, Folder 1769)
    - Woodsmall, Ruth F., 1942-1948 (Box 100, Folder 1770)
    - Woolley, Mary E., 1904-1937 (Box 100, Folder 1771)
    - Worman, E. Clark, 1941-1948 (Box 100, Folder 1772)
    - Wreford, A.T., 1946-1950 (Box 100, Folder 1773)
    - Wright, Henry Burt, 1900-1915 (Box 100, Folder 1774)
    - Wu, Yi-Fang, 1934-1947 (Box 100, Folder 1775)
    - Y (Box 100, Folder 1776)
    - Yale Divinity School, 1940-1951 (Box 101, Folder 1777)
    - Yapp, Arthur K., 1913-1934 (Box 101, Folder 1778)
    - Yergan, Max, 1948-1952 (Box 101, Folder 1779)
    - Yolland, Edgar, 1944-1945 (Box 101, Folder 1780)
    - YMCA, 1912-1954 (Box 101, Folder 1780A)
    - YMCA Retirement Fund see: Earl W. Brandenburg)
    - Yui, David Z.T., 1910-1934 (Box 101, Folder 1781)
    - Yun Chi Ho, 1910-1934 (Box 101, Folder 1782)
    - Z (Box 101, Folder 1783)
    - Zankow, Stefan, 1928-1948 (Box 101, Folder 1784)
    - Zimmerman, Walter, 1940-1946 (Box 101, Folder 1785)
    - Zwemer, Samuel Bound volume of letters to JRM from 1935 YMCA Is worldwide on the occasion of his 70th birthday, 1909-1951 (Box 101, Folder 1786)
    - Illegible signatures, 1914-1934 (Box 101, Folder 1786A)
    - Bound volume of letters to JRM from leaders in Student Christian Movement, 1922 (Box 101, Folder 1786B)
    - Bound volume of letters to JRM from the retired secretaries of the YMCA of North America, 1928 (Box 101, Folder 1786C)
    - Bound volume of letters to JRM from YMCA's worldwide on the occasion of his 70th birthday, 1935 (Box 238, Folder 1)
- Family Papers and Correspondence, Series II
  A. Genealogy and history of the Mott family
  B. Genealogy and history of the Dodge family (JRM's mothers family)
  C. J.R. Mott family correspondence: including with JRM's parents, sisters, wife, children and their families
  D. Genealogy and history of Leila White Mott's family
  E. Leila White Mott family correspondence: including with JRM's parents and sisters, her own parents and siblings, her children, and their families
  F. Leila White Mott general correspondence: alphabetically arranged
  G. Agnes Peter Mott general correspondence: alphabetically arranged
  - Genealogy and History of the Mott Family
    - Notes and documents, 1813-1975 (Box 102, Folder 1787)
    - Notes and documents - Essay by James Mott, 1904 (Box 102, Folder 1788)
    - Notes and Documents (Box 102, Folder 1789)
    - Letters ret possible relatives of JRM, 1898-1944 (Box 102, Folder 1790)
    - Memorabilia related to JRM's parents, c.1835-1909 (Box 102, Folder 1791)
    - Material related to estate of John S. Mott, 1885-1920 (Box 102, Folder 1792)
    - Memorabilia related to JRM's sisters, 1919-1948 (Box 102, Folder 1793)
    - Material related to death of Ralph Mott McAdam, 1918-1938 (Box 102, Folder 1794)
    - Information regarding JRM's children, 1945-1975 (Box 102, Folder 1795)
  - Genealogy and History of the Dodge Family
    - Letters, documents, notes, 1879-1946 (Box 102, Folder 1796)
    - Letters, documents, notes, n.d. (Box 102, Folder 1797)
  - J. R. Mott Family Correspondence
    - Letters related to family history, 1856-1911 (Box 103, Folder 1798)
    - Elmira Dodge Mott from her brothers, sister, 1862-1865, nd (Box 103, Folder 1799)
    - Elmira Dodge Mott with Harriet and Clara Mott, 1885-1907, nd (Box 103, Folder 1800)
    - JRM to parents, sisters, 1873-1885 May (Box 103, Folder 1801)
    - JRM to parents, sisters, 1885 Sep-Dec (Box 103, Folder 1802)
    - JRM to parents, sisters, 1886 Jan-Jul (Box 103, Folder 1803)
    - JRM to parents, sisters, 1886 Aug-Dec (Box 103, Folder 1804)
    - JRM to parents, sisters, 1887 Jan-May (Box 103, Folder 1805)
    - JRM to parents, sisters, 1887 Sep-Dec (Box 103, Folder 1806)
    - JRM to parents, sisters, 1888 Jan-Aug (Box 104, Folder 1807)
    - JRM to parents, sisters, 1888 Sep-Dec (Box 104, Folder 1808)
    - JRM to parents, sisters, 1889 Sep-Dec (Box 104, Folder 1809)
    - JRM to parents, sisters, 1890 Jan-May (Box 104, Folder 1810)
    - JRM to parents, sisters, 1890 Jun-Dec (Box 104, Folder 1811)
    - JRM to parents, sisters, 1891 Jan-May (Box 104, Folder 1812)
    - JRM to parents, sisters, 1891 Jun-Dec (Box 104, Folder 1813)
    - JRM to parents, sisters, 1892 Jan-May (Box 105, Folder 1814)
    - JRM to parents, sisters, 1892 Jun-Dec (Box 105, Folder 1815)
    - JRM to parents, sisters, 1893 (Box 105, Folder 1816)
    - JRM to parents, sisters, 1894 (Box 105, Folder 1817)
    - JRM to parents, sisters, 1895 Jan-Aug (Box 105, Folder 1818)
    - JRM to parents, sisters, 1895 Sep-Dec (Box 105, Folder 1819)
    - JRM to parents, sisters, 1896 Jan-May (Box 105, Folder 1820)
    - JRM to parents, sisters, 1896 Jun-Dec (Box 105, Folder 1821)
    - JRM to parents, sisters, 1897 (Box 105, Folder 1822)
    - JRM to parents, sisters, 1898 (Box 106, Folder 1823)
    - JRM to parents, sisters, 1899 (Box 106, Folder 1824)
    - JRM to parents, sisters, 1900 (Box 106, Folder 1825)
    - JRM to parents, sisters, 1901 (Box 106, Folder 1826)
    - JRM to parents, sisters, 1902,1903 (Box 106, Folder 1827)
    - JRM to parents, sisters, 1904,1905 (Box 106, Folder 1828)
    - JRM to parents, sisters, 1906 (Box 106, Folder 1829)
    - JRM to parents, sisters, 1907-1911 (Box 106, Folder 1830)
    - JRM to parents, sisters, 1912-1942, n.d. (Box 106, Folder 1831)
    - JRM to Leila White Mott, 1906 (Box 107, Folder 1832)
    - JRM to LWM, 1907 (Box 107, Folder 1833)
    - JRM to LWM, 1908 (Box 107, Folder 1834)
    - JRM to LWM, 1910, 1911 (Box 107, Folder 1835)
    - JRM to LWM, 1912 (Box 107, Folder 1836)
    - JRM to LWM, 1913 (Box 107, Folder 1837)
    - JRM to LWM, 1914, 1917 (Box 107, Folder 1838)
    - JRM to LWM, 1918, 1919 (Box 107, Folder 1839)
    - JRM to LWM, 1923 (Box 107, Folder 1840)
    - JRM to LWM, 1931 (Box 107, Folder 1841)
    - JRM to LWM, 1932 (Box 107, Folder 1842)
    - JRM to LWM, 1933 (Box 107, Folder 1843)
    - JRM to LWM, 1936 Mar-May (Box 107, Folder 1844)
    - JRM to LWM, 1936 Nov-Dec (Box 107, Folder 1845)
    - JRM to LWM, 1937 (Box 107, Folder 1846)
    - JRM to LWM, 1938 (Box 107, Folder 1847)
    - JRM to LWM, 1939 Feb-Jul (Box 107, Folder 1848)
    - JRM to LWM, 1939 Oct-Dec (Box 107, Folder 1849)
    - JRM to LWM, 1940 Jan-Mar (Box 108, Folder 1850)
    - JRM to LWM, 1940 Apr-Dec (Box 108, Folder 1851)
    - JRM to LWM, 1941 Jan-May (Box 108, Folder 1852)
    - JRM to LWM, 1941 Jun-Oct (Box 108, Folder 1853)
    - JRM to LWM, 1941 Nov-Dec (Box 108, Folder 1854)
    - JRM to LWK, 1942 Jan-Apr (Box 108, Folder 1855)
    - JRM to LWM, 1942 May-Dec (Box 108, Folder 1856)
    - JRM to LWM, 1943 Jan-Sep (Box 109, Folder 1857)
    - JRM to LWM, 1943 Oct-Dec (Box 109, Folder 1858)
    - JRM to LWM, 1944 Jan-Apr (Box 109, Folder 1859)
    - JRM to LWM, 1944 Sep-Dec (Box 109, Folder 1860)
    - JRM to LWM, 1945 (Box 109, Folder 1861)
    - JRM to LWM, 1946 (Box 109, Folder 1862)
    - JRM to LWM, 1947 Apr-Sep (Box 110, Folder 1863)
    - JRM to LWM, 1947 Oct-Nov (Box 110, Folder 1864)
    - JRM to LWM, 1948 (Box 110, Folder 1865)
    - JRM to LWM, 1949 (Box 110, Folder 1866)
    - JRM to LWM, 1950 (Box 110, Folder 1867)
    - JRM to LWM, 1951,1952 (Box 110, Folder 1868)
    - JRM to LWM, n.d. (Box 110, Folder 1869)
    - JRM from LWM, 1894-1901 (Box 110, Folder 1870)
    - JRM from LWM, 1934,1939,n.d. (Box 110, Folder 1871)
    - JRM with John L. Mott and family, 1906-1952 (Box 111, Folder 1872)
    - JRM with John L. Mott and family, 1953-1954, n.d. (Box 111, Folder 1873)
    - JRM with Irene Mott Bose and family, 1906-1928 (Box 111, Folder 1874)
    - JRM with IMB and family, 1929-1930 (Box 111, Folder 1875)
    - JRM with IMB and family, 1931-1935 (Box 111, Folder 1876)
    - JRM with IMB and family, 1936-1940 (Box 111, Folder 1877)
    - JRM with IMB and family, 1941-1947 (Box 111, Folder 1878)
    - JRM with IMB and family, 1948-1955, n.d. (Box 111, Folder 1879)
    - JRM with Frederick Mott and family, 1910-1955, n.d. (Box 111, Folder 1880)
    - JRM with Eleanor Mott Ross and family, 1918-1952, n.d. (Box 111, Folder 1881)
    - Other correspondence of JRM's children, 1914-1975 (Box 111, Folder 1881A)
  - Genealogy and History of Leila White Mott Family
    - Genealogical information, 1903-1968 (Box 112, Folder 1882)
    - LWM address books, 1947, n.d. (Box 112, Folder 1883)
    - LWM memorabilia, 1878-1950 (Box 112, Folder 1884)
    - LWM memorabilia, n.d. (Box 112, Folder 1885)
    - LWM: material related to her death, 1952 (Box 112, Folder 1886)
    - Anna White Stewart memorabilia, 1910-1945, n.d. (Box 113, Folder 1887)
  - Leila White Mott: Family Correspondence
    - LWM with her parents, siblings and their spouses, 1883-1895 (Box 113, Folder 1888)
    - LWM with parents, siblings, and their spouses, 1901-1915 (Box 113, Folder 1889)
    - LWM with parents, siblings, and their spouses, 1916-1924 (Box 113, Folder 1890)
    - LWM with parents, siblings, and their spouses, 1925-1929 (Box 113, Folder 1891)
    - LWM with parents, siblings, and their spouses, 1930-1934 (Box 113, Folder 1892)
    - LWM with parents, siblings, and their spouses, 1935-1952, n.d. (Box 114, Folder 1893)
    - LWM to the parents and sisters of JRM, 1892-18-97 (Box 114, Folder 1894)
    - LWM to the parents and sisters of JRM, 1898-1906 (Box 114, Folder 1895)
    - LWM to the parents and sisters of JRM, 1908-1918 (Box 114, Folder 1896)
    - LWM to the parents and sisters of JRM, 1934-1938, n.d. (Box 114, Folder 1897)
    - LWM to "home friends", 1893-1895 (Box 114, Folder 1898)
    - LWM to "home friends", 1896 Jan-Jun (Box 114, Folder 1899)
    - LWM to "home friends", 1896 Jul- 1899 (Box 114, Folder 1900)
    - LWM to "home friends", 1902-1911 (Box 114, Folder 1901)
    - LWM to "home friends", 1926-1948 (Box 114, Folder 1902)
    - LWM with John L. Mott and family, 1896-1952, n.d. (Box 115, Folder 1903)
    - LWM with Irene Mott Bose and family, 1906-1911 (Box 115, Folder 1904)
    - LWM with IMB, 1931-1935 (Box 115, Folder 1905)
    - LWM with IMB, 1936-1938 (Box 115, Folder 1906)
    - LWM with IMB, 1939-1940 (Box 115, Folder 1907)
    - LWM with IMB (excerpts), 1928-1940 (Box 115, Folder 1908)
    - LWM with IMB, 1941-1952, n.d. (Box 115, Folder 1909)
    - LWM with Frederick Mott firmly, 1944-1949 (Box 115, Folder 1910)
    - LWM with Eleanor Mott Ross and family, 1921-1950, n.d. (Box 115, Folder 1911)
  - Leila White Mott: General Correspondence
    - A-B (Box 115, Folder 1912)
    - C-D (Box 115, Folder 1913)
    - F-I (Box 115, Folder 1914)
    - J-L (Box 115, Folder 1915)
    - M (Box 115, Folder 1916)
    - N-R (Box 115, Folder 1917)
    - S (Box 115, Folder 1918)
    - Spencer, Mary H., 1941 (Box 115, Folder 1919)
    - Spencer, Mary H., 1942 (Box 115, Folder 1920)
    - Spencer, Mary H., 1943-1945 (Box 115, Folder 1921)
    - T (Box 116, Folder 1922)
    - Tice, Nettie E., 1943-1948 (Box 116, Folder 1923)
    - V-Y (Box 116, Folder 1924)
    - First names, fragments (Box 116, Folder 1925)
  - Agnes Peter Mott: General Correspondence
    - Primarily letters of condolence, 1953-1957 (Box 116, Folder 1926)
- Report Letters, Journals and Diaries, 1888-1942; Series III
  This series is divided into two sections. The first section contains the report letters and journals of John R. Mott, chronologically arranged. The second section contains two diaries and a few journaltype writings of Leila White Mott.
  - John R. Mott
    - Visits to colleges, universities in North America, 1888 Sep,Oct (Box 117, Folder 1927)
    - Visits to colleges of Canadian Northwest, 1890 (Box 117, Folder 1928)
    - Trip to Europe, 1891 (Box 117, Folder 1929)
    - World Trip, 1895 (Box 117, Folder 1930)
    - World Trip, 1896 (Box 117, Folder 1931)
    - World Trip, 1897 (Box 117, Folder 1932)
    - Trip to Europe, 1898 (Box 117, Folder 1933)
    - Trip to Europe, 1899 (Box 117, Folder 1934)
    - Visits to colleges, universities in North America, 1900-1901 (Box 117, Folder 1935)
    - World Trip, 1901-1902 (Box 117, Folder 1936)
    - Trip to Australasia, 1903 (Box 117, Folder 1937)
    - Trip to Europe, 1904 (Box 117, Folder 1938)
    - WSCF report letters, 1905-1906 (Box 117, Folder 1939)
    - Visits to South Africa, South America, 1906 (Box 117, Folder 1940)
    - Trip to Far East, 1907 (Box 117, Folder 1941)
    - Trip to Europe, 1908 (Box 117, Folder 1942)
    - Trip to Europe, 1909 (Box 117, Folder 1943)
    - Trip to Europe, Near East, 1911 (Box 117, Folder 1944)
    - Trip to The Netherlands, Ireland, 1912 (Box 117, Folder 1945)
    - Trip to Asia, 1913 (Box 117, Folder 1946)
    - Trips to Europe, Russia, 1916, 1917 (Box 118, Folder 1947)
    - Trips to Poland, Japan, 1920, 1922 (Box 118, Folder 1948)
    - Trip to Pacific Basin, 1925-1926 (Box 118, Folder 1949)
    - World Trip, 1928-1929 (Box 118, Folder 1950)
    - Trip to Africa, 1934 (Box 118, Folder 1951)
    - Trip to Far East, 1935 (Box 118, Folder 1952)
    - Trip to Great Britain, India, Near East, 1936-1937 (Box 118, Folder 1953)
    - Trip to India, 1938-1939 (Box 118, Folder 1954)
  - Leila White Mott
    - Diary, 1880-1887 (Box 118, Folder 1955)
    - Diary, journals, 1890-191? (Box 118, Folder 1956)
    - Journals, notebooks, 1895-1926 (Box 228, Folder 3506-3512)
- Notes and Notebooks, 1907-1937, nd.; Series IV
  The manuscript notes and notebooks of Series IV are arranged alphabetically by topic. The material within each topic is chronologically arranged.
  - Africa, 1907-1937, nd. (Box 119, Folder 1957)
  - Agricultural Missions Foundation, 1930, nd. (Box 119, Folder 1958)
  - Allied Youth, Inc., 1946 (Box 119, Folder 1959)
  - Asia, 1908-1938, nd. (Box 119, Folder 1960)
  - Australia, 1896 (Box 119, Folder 1961)
  - Australia, New Zealand, 1903, 1926 (Box 119, Folder 1962)
  - Autobiographical, 1895-1952, nd. (Box 119, Folder 1963)
  - Bible Study, 1893-1937, nd. (Box 119, Folder 1964)
  - Biographical (arranged alphabetically) (Box 119, Folder 1965)
  - Biographies of Ministers - bibliography, nd. (Box 119, Folder 1966)
  - Books written by JRM, 1947 (Box 119, Folder 1967)
  - Canada, 1897, 1935 (Box 119, Folder 1968)
  - China, 1896-1949, nd. (Box 119, Folder 1969)
  - China-Organization of YMCA, 1896-1898 (Box 119, Folder 1969A)
  - Christian Life, Christ, 1932, nd. (Box 119, Folder 1970)
  - Christianity and the economic system (Box 119, Folder 1971)
  - Christmas and gift lists before, 1925 (Box 119, Folder 1972)
  - Christmas and gift lists, 1925-1929 (Box 119, Folder 1973)
  - Christmas and gift lists, 1930-1933 (Box 120, Folder 1974)
  - Christmas and gift lists, 1934-1941 (Box 120, Folder 1975)
  - Christmas and gift lists, 1942-1954, nd. (Box 120, Folder 1976)
  - The Church, Church unity, 1898-1948 (Box 120, Folder 1977)
  - The Church, Church unity - Dallas lectures, 1941 (Box 120, Folder 1978)
  - Conferences - general, 1892-1923, nd. (Box 120, Folder 1979)
  - Conferences - with individuals - in Bulgaria, 1895 (Box 120, Folder 1980)
  - Conferences-with individuals - in China, 1901-1902 (Box 120, Folder 1980A)
  - Conferences - with individuals - in Germany, 1933-1946 (Box 120, Folder 1981)
  - Conferences - with individuals - in Hawaii, 1897 (Box 120, Folder 1981A)
  - Conferences - with individuals - in India, 1896-1937 (Box 120, Folder 1982)
  - Conferences - with individuals - in Japan, 1896-1902 (Box 120, Folder 1982A)
  - Conferences - with individuals - in Scandinavia, 1899 (Box 120, Folder 1983)
  - Conferences - with individuals miscellaneous (alphabetically arranged) Ad-Go (Box 121, Folder 1984)
  - Conferences - with individuals miscellaneous (alphabetically arranged) Ha-Mu (Box 121, Folder 1985)
  - Conferences,- with individuals miscellaneous (alphabetically arranged) Ni-Sz (Box 121, Folder 1986)
  - Conferences - with individuals miscellaneous (alphabetically arranged) To-Z, unidentified (Box 121, Folder 1987)
  - Cornell University - addresses, etc., 1895-1948, nd. (Box 121, Folder 1988)
  - Devotional/Evangelistic addresses, 1893-1910 (Box 121, Folder 1989)
  - Devotional/Evangelistic addresses, 1911-1920 (Box 121, Folder 1990)
  - Devotional/Evangelistic addresses, 1921-1930 (Box 121, Folder 1991)
  - Devotional/Evangelistic addresses, 1931-1940 (Box 121, Folder 1992)
  - Devotional/Evangelistic addresses, 1941-1942 (Box 121, Folder 1993)
  - Devotional/Evangelistic addresses, 1943-1944 (Box 121, Folder 1994)
  - Devotional/Evangelistic addresses, 1945-1950 (Box 121, Folder 1995)
  - Devotional/Evangelistic addresses, nd. (Box 121, Folder 1996)
  - Devotional/Evangelistic addresses, nd. (Box 121, Folder 1997)
  - Devotional/Evangelistic addresses, n.d. (Box 122, Folder 1998)
  - Devotional/Evangelistic addresses, n.d. (Box 122, Folder 1999)
  - Devotional/Evangelistic addresses - 1944 ? Yale lectures (Box 122, Folder 2000)
  - Drawings by ARM as a child, n.d. (Box 122, Folder 2001)
  - Eastern Orthodox Churches, 1908-1924 (Box 122, Folder 2002)
  - Eastern Orthodox Churches, 1926-1950 (Box 122, Folder 2003)
  - Edinburgh World Missionary Conference and Continuation Committee, 1909-1915, n.d. (Box 122, Folder 2004)
  - Education, n.d. (Box 122, Folder 2005)
  - Europe - miscellaneous, 1895-1949, n.d. (Box 122, Folder 2006)
  - Evangelism, 1892-1936 (Box 122, Folder 2007)
  - Evangelism, n.d. (Box 122, Folder 2008)
  - Financial matters - raising money, 1901-1953 (Box 122, Folder 2009)
  - Financial matters - raising money, n.d. (Box 122, Folder 2010)
  - Financial matters - raising money, n.d. (Box 122, Folder 2011)
  - Financial matters - records, 1907-1947 (Box 122, Folder 2012)
  - Financial matters - records, n.d (Box 123, Folder 2013)
  - Foreign Missions Conference of North America, 1927-1943 (Box 123, Folder 2014)
  - Gandhi interviews and biography, 1929-1938, n.d. (Box 123, Folder 2015)
  - Germany, 1914-1946 (Box 123, Folder 2016)
  - Great Britain, 1896-1946, n.d. (Box 123, Folder 2017)
  - Habit, n.d. (Box 123, Folder 2018)
  - Health, 1915 (Box 123, Folder 2019)
  - Honorary degrees, 1910-1931 (Box 123, Folder 2020)
  - Honors, awards, 1946-1947 (Box 123, Folder 2021)
  - Humor, n.d. (Box 123, Folder 2022)
  - India, 1912-1942 (Box 123, Folder 2023)
  - India (Box 123, Folder 2024)
  - Indonesia, 1946 (Box 123, Folder 2025)
  - Institute of Social and Religious Research, 1921, 1924, n.d. (Box 123, Folder 2026)
  - Interchurch World Movement, 1919-1920 (Box 123, Folder 2027)
  - International Missionary Council, 1920-1927 (Box 123, Folder 2028)
  - International Missionary Council, 1928 (Box 123, Folder 2029)
  - International Missionary Council, 1929-1937 (Box 123, Folder 2030)
  - International Missionary Council, 1938-1947 (Box 123, Folder 2031)
  - International Missionary Council, n.d. (Box 124, Folder 2032)
  - International Missionary Council, n.d. (Box 124, Folder 2033)
  - International situation, 1909-1938 (Box 124, Folder 2034)
  - International situation, 1940-1950, n.d. (Box 124, Folder 2035)
  - Interseminary Missionary Alliance, 1880-1884 (Box 124, Folder 2036)
  - Interseminary Missionary Alliance, 1885-1894 (Box 124, Folder 2037)
  - Interseminary Missionary Alliance, n.d. (Box 124, Folder 2038)
  - Italy, 1905-1937, n.d. (Box 124, Folder 2039)
  - James Stokes Society, 1926, 1943, n.d. (Box 124, Folder 2040)
  - Japan, 1897-1950, n.d. (Box 124, Folder 2041)
  - Jews, n.d. (Box 124, Folder 2042)
  - Korea, 1926 (Box 124, Folder 2043)
  - Lay workers, 1908-1949, n.d. (Box 124, Folder 2044)
  - Laymen's Foreign Mission Inquiry, 1923 (Box 124, Folder 2045)
  - Laymen's Missionary Movement, 1924, 1927, n.d. (Box 124, Folder 2046)
  - Leadership, recruitment, 1884-1945 (Box 125, Folder 2047)
  - Leadership, recruitment, n.d. (Box 125, Folder 2048)
  - Lord's Day Alliance, 1931 (Box 125, Folder 2049)
  - Methodist Lpiscopal Church Methodist Church, 1886-1949, n.d. (Box 125, Folder 2050)
  - Methods - Developing workers, 1908-1927 (Box 125, Folder 2051)
  - Methods - Visits 2052A Mexican Commission 1916, 1912, 1941, n.d. (Box 125, Folder 2052)
  - Miscellaneous, 1906-1944 (Box 125, Folder 2053)
  - Miscellaneous, 1945-1948 (Box 125, Folder 2054)
  - Miscellaneous, 1949-1953 (Box 125, Folder 2055)
  - Miscellaneous, n.d. (Box 125, Folder 2056)
  - Miscellaneous, n.d. (Box 125, Folder 2057)
  - Miscellaneous, n.d. (Box 125, Folder 2058)
  - Missionary strategists, n.d. (Box 125, Folder 2059)
  - Missions, 1888-1919 (Box 126, Folder 2060)
  - Missions, 1923-1930 (Box 126, Folder 2061)
  - Missions, 1931-1939 (Box 126, Folder 2062)
  - Missions, 1941-1945, n.d. (Box 126, Folder 2063)
  - Morning Watch, n.d. (Box 126, Folder 2064)
  - Moslem lands, 1909, 1924, n.d. (Box 126, Folder 2065)
  - Mott staff instructions, 1908-1946, n.d. (Box 126, Folder 2066)
  - The Netherlands 2067A Nobel Peace Prize 1946, 1909 (Box 126, Folder 2067)
  - Notebook of names and addresses, 1944 (Box 126, Folder 2068)
  - Notebook, lists of names and addresses, 1944-1953 (Box 126, Folder 2069)
  - Oberammergau Passion Play, 1910, 1930 (Box 126, Folder 2070)
  - Organizational methods, 1913, 1915, n.d. (Box 126, Folder 2071)
  - Oxford and Edinburgh Conferences, 1937 (Box 126, Folder 2072)
  - Philippine Islands, 1935 (Box 126, Folder 2073)
  - Pocket ledgers 2074A Pocket ledgers 1897-1901, 1890-1897 (Box 127, Folder 2074)
  - Pocket ledgers, 1902-1905 (Box 127, Folder 2075)
  - Pocket ledgers, 1906-1909 (Box 127, Folder 2076)
  - Pocket ledgers, 1910-1915 (Box 127, Folder 2077)
  - Pocket ledgers, 1915-1919 (Box 127, Folder 2078)
  - Pocket ledgers, 1920-1928 (Box 127, Folder 2079)
  - Pocket ledgers, 1928-1934 (Box 128, Folder 2080)
  - Pocket ledgers, 1936-1938 (Box 128, Folder 2081)
  - Pocket ledgers, 1938-1942 (Box 128, Folder 2082)
  - Pocket ledgers, 1943-1947 (Box 128, Folder 2083)
  - Pocket ledgers, 1948-1949 (Box 128, Folder 2084)
  - Pocket ledgers, 1951-1955 (Box 128, Folder 2085)
  - Prohibition, 1932-1954, n.d. (Box 128, Folder 2086)
  - Prominent people met by JRM (lists), 1922-1949, n.d. (Box 128, Folder 2087)
  - Quiet Days, 1906-1951 (Box 128, Folder 2088)
  - Race relations, 1924-1944, n.d. (Box 128, Folder 2089)
  - Roman Catholic Church, 1912-1944, n.d. (Box 129, Folder 2090)
  - Rural life, 1910 (Box 129, Folder 2091)
  - Russia - General, 1909-1938 (Box 129, Folder 2092)
  - Russia - General, 1940-1947 (Box 129, Folder 2093)
  - Russia - General, n.d. (Box 129, Folder 2094)
  - Russia - JRM Government mission, 1917 (Box 129, Folder 2095)
  - Society of Professors of Church History, 1930 (Box 129, Folder 2096)
  - South/Central America, 1906-1953 (Box 129, Folder 2097)
  - South/Central America, n.d. (Box 129, Folder 2098)
  - Student Christian work - general, 1894-1946, n.d. (Box 129, Folder 2099)
  - Student Christan work - state universities, 1910-1937, n.d. (Box 129, Folder 2100)
  - Student Volunteer Movement, 1888-1899 (Box 129, Folder 2101)
  - Student Volunteer Movement, 1901-1910 (Box 129, Folder 2102)
  - Student Volunteer Movement, 1911-1920 (Box 129, Folder 2103)
  - Student Volunteer Movement, 1921-1951 (Box 129, Folder 2104)
  - Student Volunteer Movement, n.d. (Box 130, Folder 2105)
  - Student Volunteer Movement, n.d. (Box 130, Folder 2106)
  - Student Volunteer Movement - The Traveling Secretary, n.d. (Box 130, Folder 2107)
  - Subjects of addresses, speeches, 1909, n.d. (Box 130, Folder 2108)
  - Time, age, n.d. (Box 130, Folder 2109)
  - Travel notes, itineraries, 1890-1899 (Box 130, Folder 2110)